<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interdisciplinary Materials Group at Tohoku University</title>
    <description>We focus on solid-state theory, simulation, and machine learning for quantum materials.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:40:34 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:40:34 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.10.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advanced School On Topological Quantum Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We organize and are lecturers for a summer school &lt;a href=&quot;https://icisequynhon.com/conferences/2025/toposchool2025/index.html&quot;&gt;“Advanced School on Topological Quantum Matters”&lt;/a&gt; at Quy Nhon, Vietnam on June 30 - July 5, 2025. This school aimed at advanced doctoral students, postdoctoral fellows, and early career researchers. It is the first school on strongly correlated topological quantum matter in Vietnam. The School will include introductory and advanced lectures on the following topics: Topological Band Theory, Topological Quantum Matters, Quantum Field Theory Approaches, Generalized Symmetries, and Artificial Intelligence. The schedule will leave ample room for discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This school will provide a great opportunity for students to engage with leading experts in the field. Through lectures, seminars, and discussions, participants will gain deep insights into cutting-edge developments in topological quantum materials while networking with distinguished researchers shaping the future of quantum science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Advanced-school-on-topological-quantum-matters.md/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Advanced-school-on-topological-quantum-matters.md/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topological-materials</category>
        
        <category>Quantum materials</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AI speeds up the discovery of energy and quantum materials</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our work in the AI for optical prediction and quantum material was selected by Tohoku University news, etc. with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tohoku.ac.jp/en/press/ai_speeds_up_discovery_of_energy_and_quantum_materials.html&quot;&gt;“AI speeds up the discovery of energy and quantum materials”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikken news in Japanese: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nikkei.com/article/DGXZRSP680093_V11C24A0000000/&quot;&gt;“東北大、材料発見を大幅にスピードアップできるAIモデルを開発”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: N. T. Hung et al. &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/adma.202409175&quot;&gt;Universal ensemble-embedding graph neural network for direct prediction of optical spectra from crystal structures&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adv. Mat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 2409175-1-11 (2024).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/AI-speeds-up-the-discovery-of-energy-and-quantum-materials/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/AI-speeds-up-the-discovery-of-energy-and-quantum-materials/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graph neural network</category>
        
        <category>Quantum materials</category>
        
        <category>DFT calculations</category>
        
        <category>Optic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A new approach to fine-tuning quantum materials</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our collaborative paper in quantum materials was selected by MIT news, Phys.org, etc. with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.mit.edu/2024/new-approach-fine-tuning-quantum-materials-0812&quot;&gt;“A new approach to fine-tuning quantum materials”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper was selected as a featured article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: M. Mandal et al. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.aip.org/aip/apr/article/11/2/021429/3299347/Precise-Fermi-level-engineering-in-a-topological&quot;&gt;Precise Fermi level engineering in a topological Weyl semimetal via fast ion implantation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appl. Phys. Rev.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 11, 021429-1-8 (2024).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/A-new-approach-to-fine-tuning-quantum-materials/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/A-new-approach-to-fine-tuning-quantum-materials/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Quantum materials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Propelling atomically layered magnets toward green computers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our collaborative paper in 2D magnetic materials for energy-efficient spintronics was selected by MIT news, Phys.org, etc. with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.mit.edu/2024/propelling-atomically-layered-magnets-toward-green-computers-0404&quot;&gt;“Propelling atomically layered magnets toward green computers”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper was also highlighted in the newsletter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/s44287-024-00048-3&quot;&gt;“Van der Waals magnet integration for energy-efficient spintronics”&lt;/a&gt; by Nature Reviews Electrical Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: S. N. Kajale et al. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adk8669&quot;&gt;Field-free deterministic switching of all-van der Waals spin-orbit torque system above room temperature&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sci. Adv.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 10, eadk8669-1-7 (2024).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Propelling-atomically-layered-magnets-toward-green-computers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Propelling-atomically-layered-magnets-toward-green-computers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>2D materials</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An open-source program for computing the Raman spectra</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We published an open-source code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2023.108967&quot;&gt;“QERaman: An open-source program for calculating resonance Raman spectra based on Quantum ESPRESSO”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comput. Phys. Commun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 295, 108967 (2024) by N. T. Hung, J. Huang, Y. Tatsumi, T. Yang, and R. Saito.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code is designed for computing the first-order resonance Raman spectroscopy based on Quantum ESPRESSO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Electron-photon and electron-phonon matrix elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1st resonance Raman spectra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linearly-polarized light&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Circularly-polarized light and polar plot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complex Raman tensor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open-source code can download at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nguyen-group/QERaman&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/QERaman-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/QERaman-code/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Raman spectra</category>
        
        <category>QERaman</category>
        
        <category>Quantum ESPRESSO</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stacking order and strain boosts second-harmonic generation with 2D Janus hetero-bilayers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our work in the nonlinear optical responses of 2D materials was selected by Tohoku University news, etc. with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tohoku.ac.jp/en/press/stacking_order_strain_boosts_second_harmonic_generation.html&quot;&gt;“Stacking order and strain boosts second-harmonic generation with 2D Janus hetero-bilayers”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mynavi news in Japanese: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.mynavi.jp/techplus/article/20230925-2778353/&quot;&gt;“東北大、ヤヌス型は通常のTMDよりも第2高調波が3倍以上増強することを確認”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikken news in Japanese: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nikkei.com/article/DGXZRSP662370_S3A920C2000000/&quot;&gt;“東北大、米ライス大とMITと共同で”ヤヌス型”2次元物質が波長400nmのSHGを発生することを第一原理計算で検証”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: N. T. Hung et al. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsnano.3c04436&quot;&gt;Nonlinear Optical Responses of Janus MoSSe/MoS2 Heterobilayers Optimized by Stacking Order and Strain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ACS Nano&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 17, 19877–19886 (2023).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Stacking-order-and-strain-boosts-second-harmonic-generation-with-2D-Janus-hetero-bilayers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Stacking-order-and-strain-boosts-second-harmonic-generation-with-2D-Janus-hetero-bilayers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Nonlinear optic</category>
        
        <category>2D material</category>
        
        <category>DFT calculations</category>
        
        <category>Quantum ESPRESSO</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scientists thread rows of metal atoms into nanofiber bundles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our collaborative paper in van der Waals nanofibers of atomically thin W6Te6 wires was selected by Tokyo Metropolitan University news, EurekAlert!, etc. with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://acs.altmetric.com/details/142843749/news&quot;&gt;“Scientists thread rows of metal atoms into nanofiber bundles”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mynavi news in Japanese: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.mynavi.jp/techplus/article/20230306-2609449/&quot;&gt;“都立大など、二元系TMCナノファイバー内部への金属原子を挿入する技術を開発”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shikoku news in Japanese: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shikoku-np.co.jp/prwire/detail.aspx?id=202303023533&quot;&gt;“東京都公立大学法人 無機ナノファイバーに金属原子を挿入する技術を開発”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: R. Natsui et al. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsnano.2c10997&quot;&gt;Vapor-Phase Indium Intercalation in van der Waals Nanofibers of Atomically Thin W6Te6 Wires&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ACS Nano&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 17, 5561–5569 (2023).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Scientists-thread-rows-of-metal-atoms-into-nanofiber-bundles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Scientists-thread-rows-of-metal-atoms-into-nanofiber-bundles/</guid>
        
        
        <category>DFT calculations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AI/ML for Materials</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords: Graph neutral network, Diffusion model, High-throughput calculation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;AI and Machine Learning (ML) are revolutionizing materials science, enabling faster discovery, design, and optimization of materials with desired properties, by leveraging data-driven approaches to predict properties and identify optimal compositions and structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ai-driven-materials-design&quot;&gt;AI-driven materials design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, materials discovery has mostly relied on the Edisonian trial and error approach. However, such a traditional process becomes increasingly time-consuming, leading to material from laboratory to market can take many years and is very expensive. Thus, this project aims to accelerate the exploration, design, and discovery of high-performance and low-cost quantum materials, such as 2D or topological materials, for energy-efficiency applications, including thermoelectricity, photocatalysis, and low-power electronic devices. We call this “Energy Tree”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integrated approach will combine the DFT calculations with high-throughput and artificial intelligence/machine learning (AI/ML). Compared to traditional materials discovery, the integrated approach has the potential to substantially reduce the experimental efforts needed to identify promising materials with target functionalities for the new energy quantum materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selected-publications&quot;&gt;Selected Publications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;N. T. Hung, R. Okabe,  A. Chotrattanapituk and M. Li, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409175&quot;&gt;Universal ensemble-embedding graph neural network for direct prediction of optical spectra from crystal structure&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adv. Mat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 2409175-1-11 (2024).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;N. T. Hung, A. R. T. Nugraha and R. Saito, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003290964&quot;&gt;Quantum ESPRESSO Course for Solid‑State Physics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jenny Stanford Publishing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, New York, 372 Pages, (2022).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/AI-ML-for-materials/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/AI-ML-for-materials/</guid>
        
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>DFT calculations</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Photonics in Materials</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords: Raman spectra, Photovoltaics, Photocatalysis, Second harmonic generation, Excitons effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-and-nonlinear-optical-response-of-2d-materials&quot;&gt;Linear and nonlinear optical response of 2D materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-dimensional (2D) materials are widely applied across many research areas, including photovoltaics, nanoelectronics, and thermoelectricity. Recent advances in top-down and bottom-up synthetic approaches enable the production of 2D crystals with precise and unique optical, mechanical, and electronic properties. In these applications, optical properties play an essential role. In this topic, we study the relevant fields of photonics of the 2D materials and heterostructures by the first-principles calculations, including the linear response, nonlinear response, excitons effect, nonlinear second harmonic generation (SHG), etc, for the applications on photovoltaics, water splitting, laser technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resonance-raman-spectroscopy&quot;&gt;Resonance Raman spectroscopy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resonance Raman spectroscopy is a powerful tool for characterizing 2D materials, providing insights into their electronic and vibrational properties, especially when the incident laser energy matches the material’s electronic transitions, revealing features like double resonance Raman processes and allowing for the study of electron-photon, electron-defect, and electron-phonon interactions. For example, the resonance Raman spectroscopy can reveal information about the G and 2D bands in graphene, which are related to the vibrational modes of the material. However, Raman calculations at the first-principles level are challenging due to the complexity of the interactions. We are pioneering in this field. We are pioneering in this area. We have developed two first-principle resonant Raman computational codes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nguyen-group/QERaman&quot;&gt;QERaman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://qr2-code.com/&quot;&gt;QR2-code&lt;/a&gt; to calculate the single- and double-resonance Raman spectra, respectively. In this topic, our goal is to search for new physics behind Raman spectra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selected-publications&quot;&gt;Selected Publications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;D. P. Gulo, N. T. Hung, R. Sankar, R. Saito and H. L. Liu, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.044001&quot;&gt;Exploring optical properties of 2H- and 1T’-MoTe2 single crystals by spectroscopic ellipsometry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phys. Rev. Mater.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 7, 044001-1-13 (2023).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V. V. Thanh, D. V. Truong and N. T. Hung, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsaem.2c03316&quot;&gt;Janus γ-Ge2SSe monolayer as a high-performance material for photocatalysis and thermoelectricity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ACS Appl. Energy Mater.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 6, 910-919 (2023).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S. Han, Y. Zhao, N. T. Hung, B. Xu, R. Saito, J. Zhang and L. Tong, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c03826&quot;&gt;Complex Raman tensor in helicity‑changing Raman spectra of black phosphorus by circularly polarized light&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;J. Phys. Chem. Lett.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 13, 1241–1248 (2022).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V. V. Thanh, N. D. Van, D. V. Truong, R. Saito and N. T. Hung, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2020.146730&quot;&gt;First-principles study of mechanical, electronic and optical properties of Janus monolayer of transition metal dichalcogenides&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Appl. Surf. Sci.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 526, 146730-1-8 (2020).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/photonics-in-materials/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/photonics-in-materials/</guid>
        
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>low-dimensional-materials</category>
        
        <category>DFT calculations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An easy book to learn Quantum ESPRESSO for solid-state physics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We published a textbook “Quantum ESPRESSO Course for Solid-State Physics” by Nguyen Tuan Hung, Ahmad R.T. Nugraha, Riichiro Saito.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is educationally designed for beginners in computational physics and materials science with many tutorials on Quantum ESPRESSO based on many tutorial courses in the world given by the authors. Therefore, it is very practical for students who aim to learn the first‐principles calculation. In particular, for the experimental students who wish to run the first‐principles calculation themselves to compare the experimental results of new materials directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See a preview at &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com.tr/books?id=5pKdEAAAQBAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Google book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy a full book at &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.asia/d/diorvaG&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.routledge.com/Quantum-ESPRESSO-Course-for-Solid-State-Physics-A-Hands-On-Guide/Saito-Tuan-Hung-Tresna-Nugraha/p/book/9789814968379&quot;&gt;Routledge Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source files of book can download at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nguyen-group/QE-SSP&quot;&gt;https://github.com/nguyen-group/QE-SSP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Quantum-ESPRESSO-for-solid-state-physics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Quantum-ESPRESSO-for-solid-state-physics/</guid>
        
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>DFT calculations</category>
        
        <category>Quantum ESPRESSO</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
